Register of the German subject collection, 1873-2012
Hoover Institution Archives
- UNIFIED GERMANY, 1990 October 3- (Boxes 99-126)
  - Elections
    - (Local elections), 1994 June 7
    - (Bundestag elections), 1994 October 16
      - Christlich-Demokratische Union Deutschlands (CDU)
      - Christlich-Demokratische Union Deutschlands (CDU) (Box 119)
      - Christlich-Soziale Union (CSU)
      - Deutsche Komunistische Partei (DKP)
      - Freie Demokratische Partei (FDP)
      - Grauen, Die (Box 120)
      - Grune Partei
      - Marxistisch-Leninistische Partei Deutschlands (MLPD)
      - Naturgesetz Partei
      - Okologisch-Demokratische Partei (ODP)
      - Partei Bibeltreurer Christen (PBC)
      - Partei des Demokratischen Sozialismus (PDS)
      - Partei des Demokratischen Sozialismus (PDS) (Box 121)
      - Republikaner, Die
      - Sozialdemokratische Partei Deutschlands (SPD) (Box 122)
  - Movements and organizations (Box 103)
    - General, 1990-1992
    - Bund Demokratischer Wissenschaftlerrinnen und Wissenschaftler (BdWi), 1992
    - Bund Sozialistischer Arbeiter, 1991
    - Europa-Union Deutschland
    - Gesellschaftsanalyse und Politische Bildung e.V., 1993
    - Komitee fur Gerechtigkeit
      - General, 1992
      - Pankow, 1993
    - Kuratorium fur einen Demokratisch Verfassten Bund Deutscher Lander, 1990-1991
    - Neues Forum, 1990-1992 (Box 114)
    - Solidaritatsdienst-International e.V., 1992 (Box 103)
    - Unabhangiger Frauenverband, 1991
  - Newspapers and periodicals
    - General
      - General, 1990-1991
      - Andere Welt, Die, 1991
      - Antifaschistische Zeitung, 1993
      - Anton, 1991
      - Arbeitermacht, 1990
      - Berliner Zeitung, 1990
      - Bild, Fortiest anniversary issue with articles and photos documenting important events since, 1992. 1952 (Box 104)
      - Box Extra, die, 1993
      - Deutsche Rundschau, 1990-1991
      - Dresdner, 1991
      - Effektiv, 1990
      - Europaische Zeitung, 1990-1992
      - Express, 1992
      - Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung, 1990
      - Friedenszeitung, 1990
      - Judische Korrespondenz, 1992-1994
      - Linker Kreiskurier, 1992
      - Marx-Engels Forschungsberichte, 1990
      - Mitteldeutsche Zeitung, 1990
      - Mitteldeutscher Kurier, 1990
      - Mittendrin, 1992
      - Neue Solidarit at, 1991
      - Neue Zeit, Die, 1992-1993
      - Parlament, Das, 1990
      - Pommersche Zeitung, Die, Ausiedlers' newspaper, 1992.
      - Prenzelberger, 1993-1994
      - Rabe Ralf, Der, 1992
      - Rad Zeit, 1991-1992
      - Rhein-Necker Zeitung, 1991
      - SAX, 1991
      - Scala, 1991
      - Scheinschlag, 1990-1993 (Box 105)
      - Stachel, 1990-1992
      - Tagezeitung, Die, 1992
      - Telegraph, 1991
      - Umbruche, 1993
      - Was, Wann, Wo, im Prenzelberg, 1992
      - Wochenpost, 1991-1992
      - Wurm, Der, 1991
    - Political parties and organizations
      - Christlich-Demokratische Union Deutschlands (CDU)
        - Berliner Rundschau, 1990
        - Betriebs Information, 1990
        - Deutschland am Wochenende, 1990
        - Neue Zeit, 1990
        - Zeitung zur Wahl, 1990
      - Demokratie Jetzt, Demokratie Jetzt, 1990
      - Deutsche Soziale Union, Deutsche Soziale Union-Kurier, 1990
      - Grune
        - Grune/Al, 1990
        - Grune Zeiten, 1990
        - Schoneberger Stichel, 1990
        - Stachlige Argumente, 1992
      - Marxistische Gruppe, Gegen die Kosten der Freiheit, 1991
      - Nationaldemokratische Partei Deutschlands, Deutsche Stimme, 1990
      - Partei des Demokratischen Sozialismus (PDS)
        - Berliner Linke, 1990-1991
        - Pankower Spiegel, 1991-1994
        - PDS Offene Liste Zeitung, 1990
      - Republikaner, Berliner Nachrichten, 1990
      - Sozialdemokratische Partei Deutschlands
        - Berliner Stimme, 1990
        - Zeitung am Sonntag, 1990
      - Spartakist-Arbeiterpartei Deutschlands, Spartakist, 1990-1993
      - Vereinigte Sozialistische Partei (VSP), Sozialistische Zeitung, 1990 (Box 106)
      - Vereinigung der Arbeitskreise fur Arbeitnehmerpolitik und Demokratie, Freie Tribune fur Arbeitnehmerpolitik, 1990
  - Political parties
    - Christlich-Demokratisch Union Deutschlands (CDU), 1990-1992 (Box 114)
    - Freiheitliche Deutsche Arbeiterpartei, 1990-1992 (Box 106)
    - Grune Partei, 1990-1992
    - Partei des Demokratischen Sozialismus (former SED), 1991-1993
    - Republikaner, 1990
    - Sozialdemokratische Partei Deutschlands (SPD), 1990-1993 (Box 114)
  - Politics and government (Box 106)
    - General. Includes publications relating to the Federal Republic of Germany's political and economic policies, Arranged by publisher, 1990-1991.
      - General, 1990
      - Government
        - Bundesministerium der Finanzen, 1990
        - Bundesministerium der Justiz, 1990
        - Bundesministerium fur innerdeutsche Beziehungen, 1990
        - Bundesministeriums fur Wirtschaft, 1992
        - Bundesminister fur Bildung und Wissenschaft, 1992
        - Bundesministers des Innern, 1990
        - Deutscher Bundestag, 1990
        - Presse- und Informationsamt der Bundesregierung, 1990-1991
        - Pressestelle des Bundesrates, 1990
        - Pressezentrum des Deutschen Bundestages, 1991
    - Auswartiges Amt, 1991
    - Bundestag
      - General, 1993
      - 11th Session, 1990
    - Constitution, 1990
    - Ministry for State Security (Stasi), 1992-1993
    - Opposition, 1992
    - Sachsen, 1991
  - Subject file (Box 107)
    - General, 1990-1991
    - Berlin
      - General
        - 1991-1992
        - 1993-1994 (Box 123)
      - Aktives Museum. Faschismus und Wiederstand, 1992-1993
      - Alternative lifestyles, 1993-1994
      - Berlinische Galerie
      - Literary circles
      - Pankow
      - Rent control
      - Scheunenviertel. Squatters, district renovation
      - Schloss
      - Youth
      - Wall
        - General
        - East Side Gallery. Mauerkatalog
    - Castles of Brandenburg province, 1994
    - Churches and religious organizations, 1991-1994 (Box 124)
    - Conversion of arms industry, anti-militarism
    - Cultural initiatives
    - Demonstrations, protests and gatherings (Box 107)
      - General, 1990-1991
      - Gulf War, 1991
      - Montagdemonstration, 1991
    - Ecological movement
    - Economic policies
      - General, 1991
      - Institute of German Economics, 1991
      - Labor and labor unions
        - General, 1990
        - Employment, 1991-1993
        - German Gerwerkschaftsbund, 1992
        - Gewerkschaft Handel, Banken und Versicherungen Berlin
        - Gewerkschaft Offentliche Dienste, Transport, und Verkehr, 1993
        - IG Medien Berlin, 1992
        - Stickstoffwerke AG, 1991
      - Rents for housing, 1992
      - Trade, 1991
      - Treuhand Anstalt, 1991
    - Education (Box 124)
      - General, 1990
      - Archives for the Contemporary History of GDR Research, 1990
      - Universitat Mannheim
        - General, 1990-1991
        - Allgemeiner Studenten Ausschuss (AStA), 1990-1991
    - Europe (Box 108)
    - Foreign relations
      - Britain, 1992
      - Federal Republic of Germany. Lecture given by Helmut Kohl at University of California, Berkeley, Typescript, 1991 September 13.
      - German Democratic Republic, 1991
      - United States, 1992-1993
      - Yugoslavia, 1992
    - Foreigners, asylum seekers, refugees (see also repatriation)
    - Gedenkstatte Haus der Wannsee-Konferenz, 1942
    - Government publications
    - Health
    - Herne, Prospect published by the city of
    - Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace
    - Housing, 1993
    - Human rights
      - General, 1990
      - Internationale Liga fur Menschenrechte, 1991
    - Immigration - Aussiedler, 1991 (Box 124)
    - Independent political initiatives, 1992-1994
    - International solidarity, 1992-1994
    - Judicial system, Includes manuscript relating to Erich Honecker's trial, 1992.
    - Kempinsky family
    - Koln. City plan
    - Labor unions and situation of labor
    - Left wing literature
    - Literature and art (Box 125)
      - General, 1991-1992
      - Schubert, Helga, 1990
      - Wolf, Christa, Includes criticism of her book, Was Bleibt?, 1990.
    - Luxemburg, Rosa
    - Maiziere, Lothar de, 1991 (Box 108)
    - Military
      - Anti-militarism, 1990
      - Bundeswehr
        - 1990-1991
        - 1992-1993 (Box 109)
      - National People's Army (NVA) of the former German Democratic Republic, 1991
      - North Atlantic Treaty Organization, 1991
    - National symbols. Includes phonotape cassette
    - Olympic games, Movement against (Box 125)
    - Ostdeutsches Kuratorium der Verbande
    - Personal experiences and correspondence, 1991-1992
    - Posters (postcard re-prints). Includes anti-fascist posters from the; anti-nuclear; anti-Strauss; anti-Reagan; and anti-Afrikaner, 1920's and 1930's
    - Publishing houses
      - Berliner Verlag, 1991
      - Die Nation, 1991
    - Racism, anti-racism, fascism, anti-fascism and right extremism, 1990-1993 (Box 109)
    - Religion
    - Repatriation of ethnic Germans (Box 125)
    - Right wing
    - Social justice
    - Social policy
      - "Bayerische Sozialpolitik", 1992
      - Programs
    - Stasi (Box 126)
    - Turkish and Kurdish minority
    - Unification, 1990
    - Women
      - General, 1991
      - Gegen die herrschende Klasse, 1992
    - World War II monuments
      - General
      - "Denkmal fur die ermordeten Juden Europas". Documentation on Berlin monument for Jewish holocaust victims, 1995
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS AND MEMORABILIA, 1918-1983
  Flags, stickers, flyers, newspaper issues, calendar, propaganda material, chunks of the Berlin Wall, T-shirts, fragment of Berlin Wall
  - Revolution World War I and II propaganda flyers and newspaper issues, two issues of Das 12 Uhr Blatt relating to the assassination attempt on Hitler,; student revolt material, and SPD calendar, 1918, 1932; 1944 1967; 1983 (Box 110)
  - Ephemeral material relating to the general elections; anti-nuclear propaganda, small chunks of the Berlin Wall; and one reunification T-shirt, 1983 and 1984 1983; 1990 (Box 111)
  - Ephemeral material relating to the elections of the fall of East Germany, unification and anti-fascism. Includes Champagne bottle, T-shirt, small wooden train, Stasi major's epaulettes, flags, stickers, scarves and a unity stamp, 1990 (Box 111-112, 158)
  - Large piece of the Berlin Wall (Exhibit-pavilion Exhibit Pavilion)
- AUDIO-VISUAL MATERIALS, 1983-1994
  Record, videotape cassettes, phonotape cassettes, phonotapes
  - One record issued by SPD for election campaign, 1983 (Record-cabinet Record cabinet)
  - Videotape cassettes (Tape-cabinet Tape cabinet)
    - Television coverage of the East German elections of, March 18, 1990 (Tape 1)
    - "Aufbruch 89" relating to East German political party Neues Forum (Tape 2)
    - Television coverage of the elections, October 14, 1990 (Tape 3)
    - "Brandenburg vor der Wahl" elections, October 14, 1990 (Tape 4)
    - Television coverage of the elections, December 2, 1990 (Tape 5)
    - Home video of East Germany's countryside. Includes scenes of demolished guard towers along the East-West border (Tape 6)
    - "Das war die DDR. Eine Geschichte des anderen Deutschland", documentary series by Mitteldeutschen Rundfunks on history of German Democratic Republic
      - PAL version
        - Parts 1-3 (Tape 7)
        - Parts 4-7 (Tape 8)
      - VHS version
        - Parts 1-3 (Tape 9)
        - Parts 4-7 (Tape 10)
    - "Wahlwerbespots der Bundesparteien. CDU, SPD, FDP, Bundnis 90, Die Grunen". Party TV election commercials, PAL version (Tape 11)
    - " Aus dem Bilderbuch einer Revolte". TV program on 1968 student revolt by Hessische Rundfunk, 1968, 1993
      - PAL version (Tape 12)
      - VHS version (Tape 13)
    - "Pessimismus dulde ich nicht. Christina Emmrich", "Opposition in Bildern" series. PDS film on asylum house for foreigners in Berlin, 1994
      - PAL version (Tape 14)
      - VHS version (Tape 15)
    - "Die Wende - das Ende", "Opposition in Bildern" series. PDS film on historic developments in East Germany in, 1990, 1994
      - PAL version (Tape 16)
      - VHS version (Tape 17)
    - "Beelzebub in Ingolstadt", "Opposition in Bildern" series. PDS film on "Red devil from the East" Gregor Gysi, 1994
      - PAL version (Tape 18)
      - VHS version (Tape 19)
    - "Gesichter der PDS", "Opposition in Bildern" series. PDS film profiles of Angela Marquardt, Gerhard Juttemann, Heinrich Graf von Einsiedel, 1994
      - PAL version (Tape 20)
      - VHS version (Tape 21)
  - Phonotapes (Tape-cabinet Tape cabinet)
    - Manfred Stolpe's discussion of his position and his past, Two reels, 1992 April 26.; 2 sound tape reels (Tape-cabinet Tape cabinet)
      Access
      Use copy reference number: xx741_a_0008104
      Recorded 25 Apr 1996, broadcast 26 Apr 1996
      Title: Streitgespräch STOLPE in der Gethsemane-Kirche
      Author: Alfred Eichhorn
  - Phonotape cassettes (Cassette-cabinet Cassette cabinet)
    - Speeches given by Helmut Kohl on at the Bundestag; in Dresden; and in Berlin at the Brandenburg Gate, November 28, 1989 December 19, 1989 December 22, 1989; 1 audio cassette There are two copies of this recording. (Cassette-cabinet Cassette cabinet)
      Use copy reference number: xx741_a_0009668
    - Speeches by Willy Brandt, Ibrahim Bohme and Markus Meckel on the occasion of Brandt's election as Honorary Chairman of the East ....German SPD at the Leipzig Party Convention, 1990 February 24; 1 audio cassette (Cassette-cabinet Cassette cabinet)
      Use copy reference number: xx741_a_0009674.
    - Founding conference of the Komitee fur Gerechtigkeit, 1992 July 11; 1 audio cassette
      Use copy reference number: xx741_a_0009672.
    - Speech by James Sheehan, "German Unification and the Future of Europe," Commonwealth Club, San Francisco, 1990 November 11; 1 audio cassette (Cassette-cabinet Cassette cabinet)
      Please see the Commonwealth Club of California records for a copy of this speech.
    - Peter Michael Diestel interviewed by Alfred Eichhorn, 1992 July 6; 1 audio cassette (Cassette-cabinet Cassette cabinet)
      Use copy reference number: xx741_a_0009681.
- INCREMENTAL MATERIALS (Box 114-167)
- World War I
  - Wichtige Kriegsdokumente (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Ansichten aus dem Kriegszeit (Folder 2)
  - Ausstelllungen Kriege (war posters) (Folder 3)
  - Photographies aus der Kreigszeit (Folder 4)
  - Funkerzeitungen u. Wandzeitungen-Ostfront-Westfront (Folder 5)
  - Bürgerrats Zeitungen including (Folder 6)
  - Reklame in Kriege
  - Musik in Kriege
  - Bildplakate - Kreig-Vaterlandische Unterricht Deutschlands (Folder 7)
  - Sonstige Bildplakate - Krieg-Osterreich Ungarn (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Regimentsfeiern-Nachkriegszeit (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Rüssenzeit in Ostpreussen, 1914 (Folder 10)
  - Feldgerichts-Urteile (Folder 11)
    - a) Ostl. Kriegschauplatz
    - b) Rumanscher Kriegschauplatz
  - Wichtige Mauernanschlage (Folder 12)
    - a) östl. Kriegschauplatz
    - b) rumanische Kriegschauplatz
  - Maueranschläge vom westl. Kriegsschauplatz (Box OS, Folder 13)
  - Flugwesen - luftfahrt (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - U-Bootkrieg (Folder 15)
  - U-bootkrieg u-Seekrieg (Folder 16)
  - Postwesen (Folder 17)
  - Kriegs Sparmassnahmen (Folder 18)
  - Kriegs Wirtschaft
  - Kriegswirtschaft - posters (Folder 19)
  - Wissenschaft u. Krieg (Folder 20)
  - Einstellung von Arbeitern-Transporte nach Deutschland (Folder 21)
  - Auslebungen von Mannschaften (Folder 22)
  - Ernährung (Folder 23)
  - Kriegs-Wohltätigkeit (Box 28, Folder 24)
  - Kriegs-Wohltätigkeit (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Mobilmachung, 1914 (Folder 26)
  - Kriegsanleihe (Folder 27)
  - Kriegsanleihe (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Kriegsanleihe (Folder 29)
  - Osterreich Kriegsanleihe (Folder 30)
  - Zensur (Folder 31)
  - Ordens-Zeugnisse (millitary orders and insignia) (Folder 32)
  - Kriegsbeschädigten Fürsorge (Folder 33)
  - Kriegsbeschädigten Organisationen (Folder 34)
  - Gefangen Wesen (Folder 35)
  - Gefangenen Heimkehr (Folder 36)
  - Demobilmachung (Folder 37)
  - Demobilmachung (Folder 38)
  - Pazifismus im Kriege (Folder 39)
  - Revolutionare Propaganda während des Krieges-spartakus im Kriege (Folder 40)
  - Kriegspresseamt-propaganda (Folder 41)
  - Kriegsgedichte (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Schuld am Kriege (Folder 43)
  - Schuld am Kriege (Folder 44)
  - Belgische Geheimdrucke-Geheim Propaganda (Folder 45)
  - Belgische Frage (Folder 46)
  - Krieg-auslandische Plakate - Belgisch (Folder 47)
  - Frankreich (Folder 48)
  - Amerika (Folder 49)
  - Zivil Zeitungen in Rumanien (Folder 50)
  - Prlklamierung des Königreich Polen (Folder 51)
  - Frieden von Versailles including Young Plan (Folder 52)
  - Volksentscheid - Youngplan (Folder 53)
  - Friedensvertrag - plebiscites, etc. (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - Abstimmungen im Allgemeinen grenz u. auslands deutschen (Folder 55)
  - Volksabstimmungen im Allgemeinen (Folder 56)
  - Abstimmung im Burgenland (Folder 57)
  - Abstimmung im Schleswig (Folder 58)
  - Trennung Sudeten Osterreichs (Folder 59)
  - Trennung Südtirols von Tirol and Anschluss an Deutschland (Folder 60)
  - Abstimmung in Oberschlesien (Folder 61)
  - Oberschlesien (Folder 62)
  - Ostpreussen-Westpreussen Volksabstimmung (Folder 63)
  - Abstimmung in Ost-und Westpreussen (Folder 64)
  - Rhein u.Ruhr. (Folder 65)
  - Ruhrbesetzung (Folder 66)
  - Autonomistenprozesse im Elsass (Folder 67)
- Postwar
  - Diverses (Box 10, Folder 68)
  - Verschiedenes (Period of Republic) (Folder 69)
  - Div. Volksbegehren (Folder 70)
  - Koloniale Frage (Folder 71)
  - Märs - - Mitteldeutschland, Okt. 1921 (Folder 72)
  - Rätezeit München, 1919 (Folder 73)
  - Kapp Putsch (Folder 74)
  - Hitler Putsch, 1923 (Folder 75)
  - Hamburger Oktober Aufstand, 1923 (Folder 76)
  - Bekämpfung gegen das Republik-Schutzgesetz (Folder 77)
  - Reichsexekutive Gegen Sachsen, 1923 (Folder 78)
  - Diverse Wahlen (Folder 79)
  - Wahlzeitung-Stadtverordneten-Wahlan Berlin, 25 Okt. 1925 (Folder 80)
  - Bürgerschaftswahl Hamburg, 9 Okt. 1927 (Folder 81)
  - Betriebsräte-Wahlen u. Gesetz (Folder 82)
  - Stadtverordneten Whalen, 17 Nov. 1929 (Folder 83)
  - Stadtverordneten-Wahl Altona, 25 Sept. 1927 (Folder 84)
  - Elternrats-Wahlen (Box 11, Folder 85)
  - Stadtverordneten Wahl Leipzig u. andere Orte, 17 Nov. 1929 (Folder 86)
  - Landtagswahlen, 31 Okt. 1926 (Folder 87)
  - Landtagswahl, 12 Mai. 1929 (Folder 88)
  - Mecklenberg. Landtag, 23 Juin 1929 (Folder 89)
  - Preussische Landtagswahlen (Folder 90)
  - Reichs Prasidentum Wahl, 1925 (Folder 91)
  - Prasidentenwahl, 1925 (Folder 92)
  - Reichstagwahl, 6 Juin 1920 (Folder 93)
  - Reichstag u. Bayr. Lantag wahl Stadtverordneten Wahl München 1924 (Folder 94)
  - Wahlzeitungen Reichstagswahl, 20 Mai 1924 (Folder 95)
  - Reichstagswahl, 4 Mai 1924 (Folder 96)
  - Reichstagwahl, 7 Dec. 1924 (Folder 97)
  - Wahlzeitungen Reichstagewahl, 20 Mai 1928 (Folder 98)
  - Reichstagswahl, 20 Mai 1928 (Box OS, Folder 99)
  - Reichstagswahl, 20 Mai 1928 (Box OS, Folder 100)
  - Reichstagswahl, 14.9.1930 (Box OS, Folder 101)
  - Reichstagswahl I-, 14 Sept. 1930 (Box OS, Folder 102)
  - Bildplakate Zur Sächs Landtagswahl, 12 Mai 1929 (Box 12, Folder 103)
  - Gemeinde wahl-Sachsen., 14 Nov. 1926 (Folder 104)
  - Sächs, Landtag-, 31 Okt. 1926 (Folder 105)
  - Sächs. Landstagswahlen., 22.6.1930 (Folder 106)
  - Stadtverodneten Wahlen im Sachsen., 14 Nov. 1926 (Folder 107)
  - I. Sächs Landstagswahl., 22.6.1930 (Box OS, Folder 108)
  - Volksentscheid Fürstenenteidigung. (Box OS, Folder 109)
  - Volksentscheid-Bildplakate - Fürstenabfindung (Box 12, Folder 110)
  - Politische Partien (6 folders in 1 large folder) (Folder 111)
  - Bildplakate-Rechtsorganisationen (Box 13, Folder 112)
  - Rechtsorganisationen (as opposed to Linksorganisationen) (Box OS, Folder 113)
  - Prozesse gegen Rechts (Box 13, Folder 114)
  - Diverse Parteien (Folder 115)
  - Diverse Politik (Folder 116)
  - Divers Völkische Organisation - N.S.D.A.P. Deutschvölkische Schutz-und Trutz-Bund, Anti-Semitism, etc. (Folder 117)
  - Bilder von Arbeiterführur, etc. (Folder 118)
  - Politische Führor (Folder 119)
  - Demokraten (Folder 120)
  - Deutsche Volkspartei (Folder 121)
  - Deutsche Volkspartei (Folder 122)
  - Deutschnationale Volkspartei (Folder 123)
  - Deutschnationale (Folder 124)
  - Alte Sozialdemokratische Partei Deutschlands (Box 14, Folder 125)
  - Sozialdemokratische Partei Deutschlands (Folder 126)
  - Sozialdemokratische Partei Deutschlands (Folder 127)
  - N.S.D.A.P. (Fine poster of Hitler and comrades), 1924 (Folder 128)
  - N.S.D.A.P. National Sozialistische Deutsche Arbeiter Partei (Folder 129)
  - Anti Nazi (Folder 130)
  - Zehn Jahre K.P.D. (Folder 131)
  - K.P.D. (14 folders in 1 large folder), 1919-1930 (Folder 132)
  - Opposition der K.P.D. (Lenenbund, usw.) (Folder 133)
  - Kommunistische Partel Deutschlands (Folder 134)
  - 1) K.P.D. (Kommunistische Arbeiter Partei Deutschlands) (Folder 135)
  - 2) Unionen (Allgemeine Arbeiter Union)
  - K.P.D. Rundschreiben (Box 15, Folder 136)
  - K.P.D. (Folder 137)
  - Jung Spartakus Bund (Folder 138)
  - Kommunistische Jugendlage (Folder 139)
  - Kommunistische Jugend (Folder 140)
  - Revolutionare Gewerkschafts-Opposition (Folder 142)
  - Republikan Vereine (Box 16, Folder 143)
  - Religiosche Vereine (Folder 144)
  - Liga Gegen Imperialismus (Folder 145)
  - Gegen den Kreig! (Folder 146)
  - Pazifistische Bünde (Folder 147)
  - Deutsche Friedensgesellschaft (Folder 148)
  - Friedenken Bewegung-Friedens Gesellschaft (Folder 149)
  - Krieg dem Kriege (Nachkriegszeit) (Folder 150)
  - Frauenbewegung (Folder 151)
  - Roter Frauen u. Mädchen Bund. (Folder 152)
  - Roter Frontkämpferbund (Box 17, Folder 153)
  - Arbeiter Wahren. Ersätz für Roten Frontkämpfer (Folder 154)
  - Studentenschaft u. Revolution (Folder 155)
  - Jugend Flugblätter (Folder 156)
  - Kongress der Werkätigen (Folder 157)
  - Arbeiterbewgung (Folder 158)
  - Arbeiterbewgung (Folder 159)
  - Gewerkschaften (Folder 160)
  - Gewerkschaftsbewegung (Folder 161)
  - Genossenschaften (Folder 162)
  - Genossenschaftsbewegung (Folder 163)
  - Elternratsbewegung (Folder 164)
  - Gegen Panzerkreuzer (Box 18, Folder 165)
  - Gegen Panzerkreuzer-krieg oder nachkrieg? undated (Folder 166)
  - Flieger-Zettel (Folder 167)
  - Feme-Morde-Schwarze Reichswehr (Folder 168)
  - Freikorps, usw. (Folder 169)
  - Wohltätigkeit- Zeppelin - Eckauer- Spende (Folder 170)
  - Aufrüstung - Gaskrieg (Folder 171)
  - Stahlhelm - Frontssoldatentage (Folder 172)
  - Spitzel Wesen. Secret police (Folder 173)
  - Spionage auch Nachkriegszeit (Folder 174)
  - Spionage - Prozesse der Nachkriegszeit (Folder 175)
  - Aufwertungsfrage (Folder 176)
  - Gesellschaft zur Verbreitung volkswritschaftlicher Kenntnisse (Folder 177)
  - Erwerbslosen (Box OS, Folder 178)
  - Bekampfung der Teuerung, usw (Box 18, Folder 179)
  - 4 page: "Hunger", ed. by Theodor Plievier with assistance Käthe Kollwitz, etc. (Folder 180)
  - Politische Wohltätigkeit (Folder 181)
  - Wohltätigkeit (Folder 182)
  - Volksbegehren - Volksentschied -Freiheitsgesetz (Box 19, Folder 183)
  - Wohnungsmangel-Mieterbewegung (Folder 184)
  - Sozialisierung (Folder 185)
  - Gegen die Justisz. Amnestie Forderung (Folder 186)
  - Streiks (Folder 187)
  - 1. mai (Folder 188)
  - 1928-1. Mai (Folder 189)
  - 1930 (Folder 190)
  - Mai demonstration and without year date, 1919, 1921, 1925, 1926 (Folder 191)
  - 1. Mai 1929 (Folder 192)
  - Gedenkfeiern Karl Liebknecht u. Rosa Luxemburg (Folder 193)
  - Rote Frontkämpfertage (18 folders in 1 large folder) (antifaschisentage) (Folder 194)
  - Revolutionsfeiern, 9 Nov. (Folder 195)
    - Politische Complets
    - Proteste gegen Zolte
    - Agrarfrage
  - Revolutionfeiern (Box 20, Folder 196)
  - Erste Revolutionszeit (Folder 197)
  - Revolutions Gedichte u. Lieder (Folder 198)